state.la.us 2003-12-03

# Privacy notice

Thank you for visiting INFO Louisiana and reviewing our Privacy Notice. This notice addresses the collection, use, and security of and access to information that may be obtained through use of INFO Louisiana. The following topics are covered:

Information Collected and How it is Used   
Personal Information   
Security   
Cookies   
Disclaimer   

**Information Collected and How It Is Used**

Information presented on INFO Louisiana is considered public information and may be distributed or copied unless otherwise specified. Use of appropriate byline/photo/image credits is requested. 

For site management, information is collected for statistical purposes. This system uses software programs to create summary statistics which are used for such purposes as assessing what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas. 

Personal identification information in an electronic form or an E-mail message containing a question or comment is used to respond to requests or questions. E-mail messages may be forwarded to other government employees who are subject specialists on specific questions.

Users are not required to provide personal information simply to visit INFO Louisiana or to download information. Government agencies or various services offered on INFO Louisiana may request personally identifiable information in order to provide requested specialized services, but such information is handled as it would be on an in-person visit to a government office.

**Personal Information**

Personal information is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information. 

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information, i.e., sending an email, registering or participating in a listserv, participating in a survey, or obtaining a state service online ([Louisiana E-Mall Privacy Statement](http://laemall.com/emall/security.html)). If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way effect your ability to use any other feature of INFO Louisiana. If personal information is requested on the Web site or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law. Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by E-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access. 

**Security**

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, INFO Louisiana web servers employ industry-standard methods to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on INFO Louisiana servers are strictly prohibited and may be punishable by law.

Various Web sites will be linked through INFO Louisiana. This includes Web sites of other governmental agencies, as well as Web sites of private entities. Many of these sites may operate under different privacy, quality, and security standards. Visitors to those Web sites are advised to check the privacy statements of those sites and be cautious about providing personally identifiable information without a clear understanding of how the information will be used. These links are provided as a convenience and courtesy to INFO Louisiana users. Although links from INFO Louisiana to other sites are researched and require permission from the site, INFO Louisiana does not have any authorship or authority of content or guarantee content accuracy.

**Cookies**  

To better serve our users we may use "cookies" to customize your browsing experience with INFO Louisiana. Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your Web browser. They provide a method of distinguishing among visitors to INFO Louisiana.

Cookies that may be created on your computer by using this Web site do not contain personally identifying information and do not compromise your privacy or security. The cookie feature may be used only to store a randomly generated identifying tag on your computer. You can refuse the cookie or delete the cookie file from your computer by using any of the widely available methods.

The only aspect of INFO Louisiana that creates a cookie is [Ask Louise](http://asklouise.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/asklouise.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=djmxA4hg&p_lva=&p_sp=&p_li=). Ask Louise creates a session cookie while you are using Ask Louise and keep the browser software open. The session cookie is destroyed as soon as the browser is closed.   

**Disclaimer**  

INFO Louisiana has links to other Web sites. These include links to Web sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations, and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on INFO Louisiana and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

Neither the State of Louisiana, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Louisiana warrants the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.
